{
  "entities": [
    {"id": "E0001", "name": "Dr. Elara Voss", "type": "PERSON", "summary": "A renowned astrobiologist who led the 2042 Europa Ocean Expedition to search for microbial life beneath the ice."},
    {"id": "E0002", "name": "Nova Dynamics", "type": "ORG", "summary": "A private aerospace corporation headquartered in Singapore that developed the first fusion-powered interplanetary probe in 2038."},
    {"id": "E0003", "name": "Tycho Lunar Research Outpost", "type": "LOC", "summary": "A permanent scientific base established in 2031 in the Tycho Crater on the Moon's near side."},
    {"id": "E0004", "name": "The Great Coral Revival", "type": "EVENT", "summary": "A global marine restoration initiative launched in 2029 that revived over 60% of degraded coral reefs by 2045."},
    {"id": "E0005", "name": "Project Aether", "type": "EVENT", "summary": "A classified 2033 experiment to test atmospheric carbon capture using high-altitude drones over the Pacific Ocean."},
    {"id": "E0006", "name": "Dr. Kenji Tanaka", "type": "PERSON", "summary": "The lead architect of the Mars Terraforming Simulation Facility in Iceland, operational since 2036."},
    {"id": "E0007", "name": "Global Climate Accord of 2027", "type": "EVENT", "summary": "An international treaty signed by 192 nations to achieve net-zero emissions by 2050, negotiated in Geneva."},
    {"id": "E0008", "name": "Aurora Borealis Observatory", "type": "LOC", "summary": "A geomagnetic research station located in northern Norway that monitors solar storms and auroral activity since 2025."},
    {"id": "E0009", "name": "Chief Sustainability Officer", "type": "ROLE", "summary": "A corporate executive role established in 2030 to oversee environmental compliance and green innovation in major enterprises."},
    {"id": "E0010", "name": "Dr. Mireya Cortez", "type": "PERSON", "summary": "A botanist who discovered drought-resistant genetically modified crops in 2034, significantly boosting food security in arid regions."},
    {"id": "E0011", "name": "TerraForm Inc.", "type": "ORG", "summary": "A biotech company based in São Paulo specializing in engineered soil microbiomes for Martian agriculture."},
    {"id": "E0012", "name": "Mars Transit Hub", "type": "LOC", "summary": "A modular space station orbiting Mars since 2040, serving as a transfer point for surface missions and cargo."},
    {"id": "E0013", "name": "The Solar Flare of 2039", "type": "EVENT", "summary": "A massive coronal mass ejection that disrupted global communications for 72 hours in September 2039."},
    {"id": "E0014", "name": "Director of Extraterrestrial Affairs", "type": "ROLE", "summary": "A diplomatic position created in 2041 by the United Nations to manage off-world human settlements and resource rights."},
    {"id": "E0015", "name": "Arctic Data Vault", "type": "LOC", "summary": "A secure underground archive in Svalbard storing digital backups of global cultural and scientific data since 2032."},
    {"id": "E0016", "name": "The Year of Silent Networks", "type": "DATE", "summary": "Refers to 2039, when global internet outages caused by solar activity led to a worldwide push for decentralized communication systems."},
    {"id": "E0017", "name": "Lunar Mining Consortium", "type": "ORG", "summary": "A multinational alliance formed in 2035 to extract helium-3 and rare minerals from the Moon's regolith."},
    {"id": "E0018", "name": "Dr. Amara Singh", "type": "PERSON", "summary": "A quantum physicist who pioneered the first stable quantum entanglement communication link between Earth and Mars in 2044."}
  ]
}